

Biru bin Jebat

Address

Palo Alto, CA 94301, United States

Race

Asian (Singaporean)

Profession

Senior Full-Stack developer Blockchain & NFT engineer

Email

strike10310522@gmail.com

Phone

+1 920 624 4894 Skills

Blockchain





React.js+ Redux

Excellent

Node.js

Excellent

Ruby on Rails

Very Good

C/C++, C#/.NET



Python, Django



Javascript, CSS



Php, Laravel



Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/biru-bin-jebat981031/

Github: https://github.com/strike1031

Professional Summary

I am a Computer Science candidate actively doing research and development in the blockchain space with a focus on Tendermint, Ethereum, Solana, Polygon, and Hyperledger. I have been involved in software development since I was 12 and have participated in the development of different software solutions for microprocessors, core banking, the web, and money-handling equipment. I have strong business English and years of remote-working experience with web development mainly using Mern-Stack (React.js, Vue.js for frontend and Node.js, Python, C#, Java for backend)

Blockchain: Stable Coins, Mint & Burn, Swapping, Staking, Market Platforms, Bridge, Proxy Contracts

Employment

1/2022 -7/2022

Toptal in United States

Full-Stack Engineer

- Maintained and improved the client portal React.js application.
- Strong Blockchain & crypto experience about Erc20/Erc721
- Restful API and GraphQL for building UI, AWS
- Implemented workflows and guidelines for code consistency, readability, maintainability, and testability.
- Maintain CI/CD and development environments
- Conducted R&D (research and development) for libraries and ways to improve our codebase
- Integrate with third-party systems using Cypress
- Python Django, C#, Ruby on Rails for backend with PostgreSQL, MySql, MongoDB database

Technologies: React.js+Redux/Vue.js with Javascript/typescript, HTML5, CSS3/Sass, typescript for frontend, Python Django, C#, Ruby on Rails for backend, AWS, MongoDB, Mysql, Terraform. PostgreSQL, Cypress

6/2020-12/2021

Refinable in US (Remote)

(https://refinable.com) Blockchain Developer

- Built the first biggest NFT Marketplace of digital art on Binance Smart Chain using ERC-721 for single and ERC-1155 for multi NFT and BEP-20 for governance token.
- Developed whole smart contracts from scratch and past the Audit from SlowMist.
- Implemented basic functionalities of NFT marketplace such as sale, auction, airdrop and used proxy for service fee calculation.

Technologies: React.js, Solidity, Rust, Solana, Blockchain, NFT Sale, Airdrop, Service Fee, Auction, NFT Bridge

AllianceBlock in Netherlands

- Full-Stack Engineer
 - Created templates and automatic smart contract deployment.
 - Generated Ethereum wallet.
 - Interacted with the front-end library for smart contracts.
 - Developed smart contracts for token, ratings, and airdrop.

Technologies: Amazon Web Services (AWS), AWS Lambda, AWS, Docker, GitLab CI/CD, Express.js, Node.js, JavaScript, Java, Ethereum, Solidity, Haskell, Cardano 11/2017-7/2018

Kindbody in United States

- Senior Software Developer
 - Maintained and improved the client portal React application.
 - Implemented workflows and guidelines for code consistency, readability, maintainability, and testability.
 - Conducted R&D (research and development) for libraries and ways to improve our codebase.

Technologies: Lerna, Jest, TypeScript, Redux, React

5/2017-10/2017

Upwork in United States

- Full-Stack Engineer
 - Built RESTful APIs using Flask and SQLAlchemy.
 - Wrote utility scripts in Python.
 - Integrated Webpack and React.js into Rails framework.
 - Collaborated with UI/UX team.
 - Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs.
 - Integrated and customized Material UI into AngularJS project.
 - Took part in making decisions on technologies to use.
 - Contributed to 3 Django applications.
 - Contributed to 3 C# applications.
 - Reviewed the pull requests submitted from other developers.
 - Assured that code quality is above par using code linting tools.

Technologies: Django, Node.js, Webpack, AngularJS, Vue.js, React, Laravel, Flask, Python, Sinatra, C#,Ruby on Rails (RoR), Ruby

10/2016-4/2017

VolKno in United States

- Full-Stack Engineer
 - Worked on building movie trailer rating web app.
 - Wrote Python background worker scripts that mines and feeds into database daily.
 - Worked with data scientists to resolve database design problems and provide exceptional customer service.
 - Improved interacting with MySQL using SequelizeORM.
 - Implemented full-text search for movie plot using Elasticsearch.
 - Improved analytics charts using D3.js and Highcharts.js.

- Integrated video player.
- Optimized complex database queries.
- Improved outdated react-boilerplate codebase.

Technologies: Elasticsearch, MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js, Node.js, Python, Highcharts, D3.js, Redux, React

Experience

Custom Proof of Work Blockchain

As a part of my master's thesis, I implemented a distributed proof of work blockchain in Node.js. I did a comparative analysis of the Bitcoin and the Ethereum blockchain, concluded main differences in their core blockchain way of operation, set requirements for a custom platform and developed it. I have analyzed in detail the difference of PoW algorithms and implemented my own including the miner process. While building the blockchain security considerations were made to stop malicious actors, censoring, reply attacks, etc.

Slack-like Text Messaging Web and Mobile App

Text messaging web app for healthcare teams.

It is a care coordination platform for healthcare teams, where patients and medical staff can interact.

My contributions were:

- Integrated Redux store management into React.js codebase.
- Closely worked with back-end developers to optimize existing Web technology and create the best possible user experience.
- Advocated Web interaction design best practices, with a focus on consistency and usability.
- Built reusable React.js components.
- Reviewed the pull requests submitted from other front-end developers.
- Improved live update of the app state by proper handling of WebSocket channel events broadcast.
- Collaborated with the design team to define the data structure.
- Provided consultation on functionality design and technologies to adopt.

Skills

Languages

React.js (strong), SQL, PHP, HTML, JavaScript, Solidity, Python, Go, Java, Ruby on Rails, C, C++, C#, TypeScript, Bash, CSS

Frameworks

Truffle, Laravel, Express.js, Tendermint, Windows Workflow Foundation, Redux

Libraries/APIs

Web3.js, Node.js, REST APIs, jQuery, Socket.IO, React Tools

Git, Hyperledger Indy, BTC Wallet, Docker Compose, VS Code, Slack, MQTT, WebStorm, PhpStorm

Platforms

Blockchain, Ethereum, Blockchain Platforms, Hyperledger Composer, Linux, Docker, Hyperledger Fabric, MacOS, Hyperledger, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Firebase

Storage

MySQL, BigchainDB, Redis, Memcached, MongoDB, PostgresSQL

Other

Elliptic Curve Cryptography, Public-key Cryptography, DApps, Smart Contracts, Cryptocurrency, Distributed Ledgers, Cryptocurrency APIs, Ethereum Smart Contracts, Cosmos SDK, Customized Blockchains, Blockchain Architecture, Solution Architecture, HD Wallets, Quorum, Scaling, Cryptographic Protocols, Applied Cryptography, Cryptography, Bitcoin, IPFS, ERC20, ERC721, ERC827, ICO, Distributed Systems, Chatbots, Cryptocurrency Wallets, Cryptocurrency Development, Data Structures, Algorithms, Mobile Wallet, IEO, Web 3.0, Oracle Service Bus (OSB), Workflow, ERC-20, ERC-721, WebSockets, Ark.io, AWS

09/2016-05/2020

Education

National University of Singapore

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Languages

English - Fluent